Hardie Parham | Senior Project Engineer

Team-focused engineer with 8 years of proven experience in Project Management and Structural Design. Quick-learning professional with excellent technical and communication skills. Possibility to obtain a PE license within 6 months of hire. Open for positions in Nashville TN, hybrid, or remote possibilities.

Experience

Toyota

Senior Project Engineer

08/2023 - Present Georgetown, KY (Remote)

- Directly lead multiple concurrent large-scale industrial construction projects of up to \$50 million.
- · Provided experience in plant planning project management, construction, and building design to ensure projects were designed and built to quality, cost, schedule, and safety KPI's.
- · Developed criteria for MEP, Fire Protection, Structural, and Civil design of buildings as a Subject Matter
- Managed and mentored a dedicated team of engineers, construction coordinators, and other project personnel.

Civil Engineer Specialist

01/2021 - 08/2023 Brussels, Belgium (On-Site)

- Lead Pan-European manufacturing activities to ensure environmental compliance, minimize safety risks, and contribute to performance improvement through technical support and cross-company collaboration.
- Directly lead multiple large-scale construction projects of up to €20 million from tendering, throughout construction, to completion.
- · Created and reviewed key project documentation and stadards, such as cost estimations, project master schedules, civil kanban, change order requests, snag lists, and project completion reports.
- Developed a cost database system for Toyota construction projects, utilizing Python, SQL, and excel.

Stantec Inc.

> Structural Project Engineer

05/2019 - 11/2020 Plano, TX (Hybrid)

- Lead engineer for the complete structural design of steel and concrete structures.
- Lead construction administration phase including field reviews and coordination, review of change orders, clarifications and RFI responses as required.
- Ensured company standards, quality assurance, and quality control procedures of Revit, AutoCAD, and BIM360 were followed during drawing production.
- Supported senior and intermediate members of the production team, as well as having direct coordination with lead architects.

RLG Consultant Engineers

> Structural Project Engineer

07/2017 - 04/2019 Dallas, TX (On-Site)

- Designed structural members of various materials including steel, concrete, masonry, and timber with relevant design codes and software assistance.
- Drafted structural models and details in Revit and AutoCAD.
- Lead multiple concurrent projects through the construction administration phase including being the primary point-of-contact, reviewing shop drawings, and responding to RFI's through Procore.

Structural Engineering Intern

06/2016 - 07/2017 Dallas, TX (On-Site)

Education

Southern Methodist University

Class of 2017 University Park, TX Bachelor of Science, Civil Engineering Bachelor of Science, Mechanical Engineering

Personal Info



Nashville, TN



M hparham865@gmail.com



(+1) 615-973-3809



In Linkedin.com/in/hardieparham865



HardieParham.com

Software

MS Excel

MS Suite

Bluebeam Revu

RISA 3D

RAM Structural

SP Column

Tekkla Structures

BIM

Revit

AutoCAD

Procore

Autodesk Build

Programming

VBA

Python

C#.NET

GDScript

Google AppsScript

Certifications

OSHA 30 Safety

OSHA Subpart R

Engineer-In-Training (EIT)

Building Codes

Steel - AISC 15

Concrete - ACI

Timber - NDS

Loading - IBC, ASCE 7

Soft Skills

Technical Communication

Project Management

Budget Management

Cost Estimation

Construction Administration

Collaboration